FELIPE MOBUS

personal information

Felipe Mobus, Brazilian, age 30

Porto Alegre / RS - Brazil

fmobus@gmail.com

http://github.com/fmobus

http://fmob.us

education

2010 BSc. Economic Sciences at UFRGS (Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul)

Porto Alegre - Brazil (on hold)

2003 - 2008 BSc. Computer Science at UFRGS

Porto Alegre - Brazil

2006 - 2007 Exchange student at TU-Kaiserslautern (Technische Universität Kaiserslautern)

Kaiserslautern - Germany

professional experience

2012 - current Consultant Developer at **ThoughtWorks**, tasked with development and delivery

of custom solutions for enterprise clients. ThoughtWorks is a global consulting and project delivery company known for its contributions to agile methodologies.

Technologies: java, ruby, javascript; rails, android; mongo

2007 - 2012 Programmer at **Propus**, tasked with maintenance, support and development of Porto Alegre - Brazil several scripts and applications. Propus' main focus is outsourcing system.

several scripts and applications. Propus' main focus is outsourcing system administration tasks, with developers contributing in more complex cases.

Technologies: python, ruby, php, postgres; mysql; asterisk

2006 - 2007 Undergraduate research assistant at **AG-DBIS** under Prof. Theo Härder. tasked with the research, design and implementation of techniques for XML document

summarization for the XTC project - a Java-based Native XML Database System.

Technical report (also final BSc. Project) is available on-line¹.

Technologies: java; xml

2005 – 2006 Developer at **Associação Software Livre.Org (ASL).** ASL is the NGO

2007 – 2008 responsible for FISL, the largest free software conference in Latin America.

Porto Alegre – Brazil Tasked with development, support, maintenance and operation of the systems

used for attendants' registration at FISL 7, and acting as external consultant

as volunteer consultant developer in more recent years.

Technologies: php, mysql, python, postgresql, javascript

technologies, skills and competences

ruby Current language of choice for projects and general hacking. Used for large-scale projects at work, powered by popular frameworks like **rails** and **sinatra**. Great fan of **rspec**.

javascript Experienced with **jQuery**, but nowadays more inclined to use more powerful frameworks like **angular**. Also experimenting with tools like **d3** and server-side fun with **nodejs**.

java Working currently with large-scale **android** applications. Also used in the past in academic settings.

python Used in several projects in the past, especially with **django**.

databases Experience in mysql, postgresql, mongodb.

TDD / **BDD** Applied the methods and concepts of both using **rspec**, **cucumber**, **jasmine** and other tools.

architectures A big fan of **service-oriented architecture**, especially when **REST** is involved, and always eager to discuss new ideas. Well-versed in UNIX principles and tools.

teamwork Quite used to working in agile teams, having practiced **scrum**, **kanban** and other mixed/evolutionary approaches.

also I also know my way around php, haskell, c, pascal and even some cobol

personal pet projects (all code available on github - work in progress)

observapoa A scrapper for statistical data about Porto Alegre https://github.com/fmobus/observapoa

bikepoa-lite Lightweight page for watching Porto Alegre's bike sharing program situation http://bikepoa.heroku.com

bikepoa-temporal Lightweight tool to visualize the usage of BikePOA program throughout the day. http://bikepoa-temporal.fmob.us/

mobilisign Tool for daydreaming designs of public transportation networks

language skills²

	listening	reading	interaction	speaking	writing
portuguese	mother tongue				
english	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
german	B1	B1	B1	A2	B1
spanish	B2	C2	B1	B1	A2

about me

I regard my self as a responsible and proactive person, having being able to exercise my dedication in several different projects throughout my professional life. I consider myself open to new experiences, specially with regards to meeting new people and understanding different cultures.

I like to constantly exercise my analytical skills by dissecting real-world problems in our societies, and coming up with possible solutions, fostering better discussion of the subject, and hopefully inspiring others.

I am a great enthusiast of free software and open data movements, having worked as a volunteer for the former for several years, and doing my share of hacking around the latter. I believe that knowledge sharing and administrative transparency are essential tools for building societies that are both more efficient and more equitable.

² all levels according to the European language self-assessment grid, available at http://goo.gl/Q9aCw